# Curriculum Vitae

## Pawel Sawicz

## Personal Informations

Telephone +44 079 403 287 80
E-Mail pawel@sawicz.eu
Blog pawel.sawicz.eu

GITHUB github.com/pawelsawicz

## Profile

Senior Software Developer specialising in distributed systems and building products. Crazy about learning new things, but balanced when taking a risk. In spare time trying to understand type theory and constructive logic. Heavily involved in .NET community, co-organizer virtual conference, moreover attendee and speaker of several conferences around Europe.

## Work Experience

Period September 2019 — Present

EMPLOYER Checkout.com London, United Kingdom

JOB TITLE Senior Software Engineer

Reconciliation project

Period March 2016 — August 2019

EMPLOYER Zopa London, United Kingdom

JOB TITLE Software Engineer

Splunk

Currently working on core part of Zopa business. Responsible for extracting microservices out of the monolith. Being involved in creating infrastructure and architecture of new services. Overview of technologies: NancyFx, Owin, Microservices, CQRS, EventSourcing, DDD, Jenkins, Packer,

Period July 2014 — February 2016

EMPLOYER JustGiving London, United Kingdom

JOB TITLE API Developer / Evangelist

Being involved in forming API team and shaping its form. I am very proud to have founded and grown the community arund the JG public api. I helped out and hosted events and international hackathons. To technical side of role belonged: creating architecture of API, maintaining and monitoring health of API, supporting customers in case of technical problems. Many contribution to core JustGiving codebase, re-factoring old parts of API, writing TDD. Overview of technologies: NancyFx, WebApi, Owin, ASP. MVC, Microservices, CQRS. Heavily worked in cloud enviroment, Amazon Web Services, used tools like: Raygun, Kibana, Chef, Vagrant, GO CD

Period July 2013 — June 2014

EMPLOYER Neurosys Wroclaw, Poland

JOB TITLE Junior .NET Developer

Involved in maintaince and development of new features. Writing unit tests to cover fragile parts of the code. Worked as fronted and backend developer. Responsible for implementing RWD in two projects, worked with knockout and

ASP.NET MVC/Web API

Period June 2011 — September 2011, August 2012 — September

2012

EMPLOYER Chroma.pl Zary, Poland

JOB TITLE Junior .NET Developer

Responsible for one major feature addon. Created unit test to cover code. Worked with 'ling to excel' library. Prepared SQL queries. Created library that checks the e-mail, by

RCPT protocol.

#### **EDUCATION**

Period October 2011 — February 2015

Degree Bachelor of Science

UNIVERSITY Wroclaw University of Technology
FIELD Electronic & Telecommunication

Period October 2018 — January 2021

DEGREE Master of Science
University University of Oxford

FIELD Computer Software Engineering

## SKILLS

LAST THREE MONTHS

Frameworks NancyFx, ASP.NET MVC, WebApi

DATABASES NHibernate, MSSQL

Tools TeamCity, Go CD, Chef, Vagrant, Terraform,

Swagger, Raygun, Kibana

#### FUNDAMENTAL KNOWLEDGE

Frameworks .NET

Programming Languages C#, JavaScript, SQL

Tools Git, SVN, Log2Console,

PRACTISE Unit Tests, TDD, SOILD, Mutation Testing LIBLARIES jQuery, NUnit, FluenAssertions, TinyloC, Au-

tomapper, NLog, RestSharp

## Activities

- Active memeber of .NET Group (PWr Wroclaw)
- Imagine Cup participant (2012, 2013 editions)
- 2012 edition Tourist Guide

Web application which provide information about travelling and sightseeing.

- 2013 edition - BusCatcher

Windows Phone 7 application which use external API to gather information about current position of public transport vehicles

- dotNetConfPL co-organizer

First polish virtual conference about .net - 200 attendees

#### LANGUAGES

ENGLISH Fluent Polish Native